Hi! I'm an aspiring UX designer with seven years' experience in fashion design and ecommerce, including extensive experience in marketing and sales within retail, wholesale, and consumer goods industries.

Monroe, NY 1.845.325.6761 jillianmazzola@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/jill-mazzola behance.net/jillmazzola github.com/jillmazzola jillmazzola.github.io/jill

### **Education**

CareerFoundry UX Design Certification, August 2020

Intensive project-based training program with a focus on research, UX design, and frontend development

**Project 1: Challenge Accepted** 

- Designed a mobile application that allows users to play a scavenger hunt
- Identified a problem statement, did competitive analyses, and wrote business requirements & user stories
- Constructed user personas, illustrated user flows & journey maps, and built a mobile-first design plan
- Worked in iterations: Built a sitemap, low- and high-fidelity prototypes, and eventually interactive prototypes
- Wrote a usability test plan and script, conducted interviews & A/B tests, and made plans for future design efforts
- Applied Gestalt Principles, built a style guide & pattern library, conducted peer review for the final prototype - Filmed and published a video presentation of the prototype

Outcome of project: A functioning prototype that demonstrates my grasp of user-centered design, generative & evaluative research, information architecture, iterative prototyping, and design presentation.

Tools and Technologies used: Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Optimal Workshop, Usability Hub Project 2: Portfolio Site Design

- Designed a writing portfolio website for me and my writing partner.
- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build the site
- Conducted user and accessibility testing to improve usability

Outcome of project: A fully functional portfolio website (see it at jillmazzola.github.io/jessica-jill/) Tools and Technologies used: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Atom

Parsons The New School for Design BFA Fashion Design, May 2014

Chase Scholars Program; Dean's List, Saks Fifth Avenue, and BFA Scholarships Nominee, Portfolio of the Year, Parsons the New School for Design, 2014

## Experience

Bombfell, Inc., New York, NY

Nov 2015 - Present Mar 2018 - Present

- **Merchandising Coordinator** - Assess clothing styles for fit and quality
  - Manage the internal and client-facing item web pages using proprietary software
  - Authorize, place, and track purchase orders using Microsoft Excel and G Suite - Maintain vendor communication to acquire (and edit!) item images and resolve issues
  - Manage our internal Instagram to keep the styling team informed of inventory updates
  - Conduct trend research and evaluation - Highlight: Recently cut costs by identifying unnecessary spending on sample POs
- Highlight: Trained and mentored a subordinate employee for the first time!

**Assistant, Special Projects** 

May 2017 - Mar 2018

- Conducted extensive customer research via comparison shipping, ethnographic field interviews, and data analysis
- Worked on a cross-functional team to develop two private label clothing lines perfectly suited for the Bombfell user
- Worked with vendor partners to direct and approve final designs for private label lines
- Managed inventory and imagery for Bombfell's collaboration with JC Penney
- Highlight: Streamlined team processes to improve efficiency

Men's Stylist Nov 2015 - May 2017 Styled personalized packages for customers based on user profiles, purchase history, sales

- data, and feedback using proprietary software
- Worked with the customer experience team to resolve issues

Condé Nast Media Group, New York, NY

Jan 2015 - Sept 2015

#### **Associate Manager of Marketing**

- Conceived and managed various creative digital campaigns from initial request and written proposal through execution using Apple Keynote
- Created digital files and renderings for on-location events using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- Processed invoices and facilitated blogger activations - Mitigated issues with clients, agency partners, and vendors
- Planned and prepared for several multi-day events across the country

Cygnet Studio, Inc., New York, NY **Studio Assistant** 

Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

- Prepared fabric and materials for construction: patterning, cutting, hand stitching, and custom treatment

- Applied couture hand treatment for garments: beading, applique, hot-fit application, etc.

- Maintained stock and specialty fabric and reference garments

Eric Winterling, Inc., New York, NY Studio Assistant

Jan 2014 - Aug 2014

# Maintained stock and specialty fabric, reference garments, and patterns

- CAP, LLC, Ramsey, NJ Media Lead
  - Designed all branding materials including logo using Adobe Illustrator - Designed and produced all print and digital advertisements, posters, flyers, competition pieces

- Content production for business partners: in-store signage and print advertisements

Ford + Condé Nast Parsons Design Lab, New York, NY

Jun 2014 – Sept 2014

Aug 2012 - Aug 2015

## **Design Fellow**

- Along with 4 other fellows, produced a fashion collection in celebration of the 50th anniversary of the Ford Mustang
- Focused on materials and fabric experimentation
- Lead team organization and communication with stakeholders

Royal Society of the Arts Winner, US Student Design Award, Textiles April 2013

Ongoing

Jun 2020

Feb 2014

Sep 2014 – Jun 2016

- Independent Project: explored a textile printing system that extends a fabric's use phase

Freelance Digital Projects Paul J. Mazzola, Inc., Hackensack, NJ - Design all branding materials including logo (for use on business cards, invoices, and website)

using Adobe Illustrator - Select fabrics for special projects

- Highlight: Recently launched throw pillow program using Shopify Custom Boozy Creations, Staten Island, NY

- Designed all branding materials including logo (for use on business cards and social media)

using Adobe Illustrator Handmade with Love, Central Valley, NY

- Designed all branding materials including logo and tags (for use on business cards, product

labels, and print signage) using Adobe Illustrator KinderClimbers, Chester, NY

- Designed all branding materials including logo (for use on business cards, video content, and website) using Adobe Illustrator

## **Expertise**

**UX | Product Skills** - Competitive Analysis

- Business Canvas Design
- Product Development
- User-Flow Mapping
- Personas, Mental Models
- Product Requirements
- Qualitative & QuantitativeResearch - User Research
- Competitive Analysis
- Heuristic Evaluation
- Prototyping Across Fidelities - Interviews & Surveys
- User Centered Design
- Content & Design Strategy - Information Architecture

- Basic HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

- **Fashion Skills** 
  - Fashion Design & Construction - Apparel Pattern Development
    - Garment Fitting
    - Illustration
    - Private Label Development - Merchandising
    - Inventory Management
    - Couture Handwork
    - Fabrication: Weaving, Felting, & Knitting
    - Millinery
    - Flats & specs

## **Programs**

 Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, InDesign, Bridge, Character Animator, Premiere Rush

- Marvelapp - UserTesting
- UsabilityHub
- Optimal Workshop
- Pointcarre - Keynote
- Microsoft Suite
- Google Suite